Here's one way to define "print_numbers":
下面是一种定义 print_numbers (打印数字) 的方法
so we're going to make a procedure using "def".
我们将使用 def (定义) 写一个程序
It takes 1 input.
程序要一个输入
We'll use the name "n" for our input.
我们用 n 来代表输入
That's the number that we go up to.
也就是我们将输出的最后一个数字
Now, to do the loop, we need to have a new variable
现在 要写这个循环 我们需要一个新变量
that keeps track of the loop iterations.
来记录循环迭代
We'll use "i" for that, and we start with 1--that's the first number to print out.
我们用 i 来指代新变量 从1开始 也就是打印出来的第一个数字
We need the loop now, so we have the "while"
现在我们需要 while 循环
and the test that we want is we want to keep going,
我们想要的判断是
up to and including the number, "n".
能让循环一直继续到 n (包括 n )
So we want to print the numbers, all the way from 1 up to and including "n".
我们想要打印出从1到 n (包括 n ) 的所有数字
So our test will now be a less than or equal to test.
所以我们的测试将是一个小于或等于判断
We want to keep going as long as "i" is less than or equal to "n".
只要 i 小于或等于 n 我们就希望循环继续
Once "i" gets bigger than "n", that's when we should stop.
当 i 大于 n 循环就停止
What we do in the loop body is print the value of "i"
循环主体语句是打印 i 的值
and add 1 to "i".
然后让 i 加1
We don't need to return anything; the only point of the procedure,
我们不需要返回任何值
as we were asked to write it, was to print out the numbers.
程序的唯一目的就是打印出数字
So now let's do a test: we'll print the numbers up to 3,
现在让我们做一个测试：我们将打印从1到3的数字
and there we get the output, printing the numbers 1, 2, 3.
所以输出就是打印出 1, 2, 3
There are lots of other ways we could have written this.
我们可以用很多不同的方式来写这个程序
Another approach would be to start with "i" equals zero,
另外一种方式就是从 i 等于0开始
make the test condition "i" is less than "n".
让判断条件为 i 小于 n
So now we're stopping as soon as "i" is equal to "n".
所以当 i 等于 n 时 循环就会停止
For this to print out the correct numbers, though, now we need to move the print.
要打印出正确的数字 现在我们要移动一下 print 的位置
We want the print to be after we added 1 to "i",
把 print 放在让 i 加上1之后
so the first number we print is supposed to be a 1, which will be the case here.
所以打印出来的第一个数字应该是1
And the final number we print should be "n", which is the case here.
打印出来的最后一个数字应该是 n
Once the value of "i" is "n", this test will be False
当 i 的值等于 n 判断就为假
and we don't go through the loop anymore--so
循环就不再继续
when we run this, we get the same result, printing 1, 2, 3.
当我们运行这些代码 得到的结果是一样的 即打印出 1, 2, 3
So as another test, let's see what happens when we pass in zero.
下面我们看看 如果传入0 结果会怎样
And when we run this, it doesn't print anything.
程序什么都不会打印出来
That's because when "i" is zero, "i" less than "n" evaluates to False.
因为当 i 等于0 i 小于 n 为假
Zero is not less than zero, so we don't go through the loop at all
0不小于0 所以循环不会执行
and don't print anything--which seems like a pretty sensible thing.
程序什么都不打印 这似乎挺合理
Since we said print the numbers between 1 and the target number,
因为我们想要打印出从1到目标数
if the target number is zero, not printing anything sort of makes sense.
如果目标数为0 不打印任何数字是有道理的